You won't get away with this!
That looks like the Frankie family.
Hey, those are our bags! How'd they get them?
Money! My money!
Galley Law Company, a grand site, dock number one!
Hold it right there, Pauly!
You're not getting away this time!
I'm telling you, I'll get you the money!
You just have to wait a little longer!
Is that...?
Yes, it's Pauly.
The debt collectors are after him again.
Ugh! Where are you going with our money?
That would be real nice if you're lending us 200 million berries like that!
Bunch of cowards! I'm gonna make you pay!
Why'd you give our money to those guys?
What do you take me for? I didn't give those jerks anything! They stole it!
What?
Give us the money!
For the last time, I can't give you money if I don't have it!
Stop making excuses and pay up!
You're gonna chase me all the way to my grave, aren't you?
Jaggera's been just in time, too!
Hyah!
Rope!
Action!
Hey, that's one of the ship rides from Galley Law, ain't it?
Sorry, fellas, but I gotta borrow those Jaggera's now!
Time for my round turn!
hinaus behaviour
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Waaaah!
Ugh...
Ha ha ha.
Ugh!
You punk!
Just wait!
We'll get you next time!
So long, gentlemen.
It was a wonderful race, as always.
Take care, and maybe you can try again next week!
Goddammit.
Ugh!
I gotta admit, for a Jagera, you sure have a good sense of dramatic timing.
Hmm.
That was close.
Those shipwrights of yours have got some pretty fancy moves.
That they do.
Hey, buddy!
Thanks for the help!
I was starting to think we'd never see our money again!
Money?
Oh.
It must mean this.
Hello!
You've gotta be kidding me.
Hey!
Come back here!
I'll take care of this!
Jerk stealing our stuff!
I'll get your money back!
Huh?
Wait.
Pigeon?
This is a manly room, if ever I've seen one.
And clean as a whistle, too.
Still, these floorboards are showing some wear and tear.
What do you think you're doing tearing apart our ship?
Oh.
Woke you up again, didn't I?
Don't worry.
I'll put things back together once I check under the floorboards.
Ow!
Okay, let me go!
Let me go!
Take it easy!
Jeez!
I'm not gonna run away!
You got me!
You win, alright?
I was lucky enough to find that money and you screw it up.
Better watch your back, Lucci.
I'll remember this.
Don't pay back your debt with someone else's money, idiot!
Have you no shame?
Hey, I happened upon that money fair and square!
Stealing from thieves is still stealing!
I didn't steal anything.
I was just borrowing the Yagata, that's all.
Looks like they're back.
That's great.
I'm glad things worked out for you, Usopp.
Worked out for me?
That $200 million was for ship repairs, remember?
That's right!
And all you did was sit there and stare like a fool while it nearly got carried away!
I know, but the business said he'd handle it.
Well, that was embarrassing.
Rest assured we will deal with our employee appropriately.
Allow us to handle this so there's no bad blood between you.
Although Polly's behavior was reprehensible, it's fortunate that he saved your money from the Frankie family.
Well, I guess you could look at it that way.
No harm done, right?
So, who is this Frankie family?
Do they rob from everyone they run into or just us?
Well, it depends, but normally they dismantle ships.
You mean they're workmen?
I don't know about you, but I'd never hire a team that looks like that.
Indeed.
But they're not just ship dismantlers, they're also bounty hunters.
Every time they find out there are pirates in town, they cause quite a ruckus.
To put it simply, they're just a public nuisance.
Not only do they collect bounties on the pirates they defeat,
they also take possession of their ships.
Afterwards, they dismantle them and sell whatever parts they can on the open market.
It may seem underhanded, but for them, it's good business.
What a bunch of jerkwads!
It's like they're trying to dismantle the whole pirate lifestyle!
Well, if they catch you, they will certainly bleed you dry.
I don't know, those guys look too weak to do anything to us!
The men you saw were underlings.
Frankie, the leader of the group, is not nearly as harmless.
If I were you, I would avoid him at any cost.
Crap!
If it wasn't for that shipwright, we would've had it!
Get in there, bro!
Oh yeah, I think I'm gonna make it.
Hey! You know where the Straw Hats are at right now?
No, uh, I guess they might still be over at dock one.
Here you go, Iceberg! Do with them as you will!
I'm here, you can let go!
Excellent work as always, Lucci.
Truly! I can't apologize enough for the actions of this, Ulf!
Go!
Ah! It is sulking!
Tell the nice people that you're sorry, Ulf!
That pigeon really has it out for that dude, doesn't he?
So the little bird talks, but the guy in the hat doesn't?
Anyway, I'm just glad we got our money back.
Oh, so these belong to you, huh?
Good thing I was around.
Yeah, thanks a lot!
If you wanna thank me, give me ten percent!
Again! I'm quite sorry!
This imbecile is addicted to gambling, you see!
He's racked up such a massive debt
that it's made him lose sight of everything but greed!
I don't care about him!
I wanna know why you're talking!
I've had about enough of you running your mouth, Lucci.
This'll shut you up!
Rope!
Action!
Coo-ca-loo-ca-coo!
Bowline!
Punishment!
Oh no! He's serious, isn't he?
The blind and sinker!
Ha ha ha!
Is he okay?
Well, this is nothing new.
Whoa! Check it out!
I thought he landed on his head, but he stomped himself with his arm!
Wow!
Not only that, but he dug his hand into the ground!
What, does he have fingers of steel or something?
These guys are just shipwrights. What do they need all these crazy powers for?
Hey! You with the goggles on your head!
Huh?
Listen, man. Think about this for a second.
That guy wasn't the one saying all that mean stuff.
It was the pigeon!
The bird could say whatever it was!
Actions speak louder than words and Lucci's the one who hit me!
Yeah, but the pigeon made him hit you because he's too much of a coward to do it himself!
Hey, pigeon!
Get down here and fight your own fights!
Say something!
Hey!
Oh, you want some more?
I'll take you on any time!
Enough, Paulie!
Coo-coo-loo-coo!
Please excuse us for all the fuss!
I'm Rob Lu...
I mean, my name's Hattery!
And this is Rob Lucci!
We both welcome you to Galilaw's factory!
Coo-coo-loo-coo!
Hold on.
The pigeon almost introduced himself as that guy, didn't he?
Oh, cool!
This is the ventriloquism act, isn't it?
Really?
You were the coolest trash-talking pigeon ever!
Even I couldn't tell it was you and I'm usually pretty sharp!
No, please!
It's really nothing special at all!
Coo-coo!
He's just a weirdo who doesn't know how to talk to people on his own!
Hold on a second!
What does that woman think she's doing?
Huh?
What do you mean?
Have you no shame?
Huh?
Don't play dumb with me, you harlot!
I can see way too much leg!
Cover up and show a little decency, will ya?
This duck is a man's workplace, you know?
Now, now, Polly.
Let's calm down.
You too, Khalifa!
How many times have I told you those clothes of yours are not appropriate?
If you want to look professional, you should wear pants,
or at least ankle-length skirts!
This guy's got issues.
He's serious, isn't he?
Well, enough of that.
Let's open the gate and start the tour already.
That's just about the biggest door I've ever seen!
And, whoa!
You have to open that thing by hand?
Wait!
Those two can't open that on their own, right?
Whoa!
I guess they can!
Well, each dock only has five foremen, and despite their peculiarities,
these two are both talented enough to hold a position at dock one.
Kaku, who you met earlier, is a foreman, too.
In a place like this, talent is the only thing that matters.
So even if they're a bit strange, we don't mind.
They are pretty weird, though.
Ha!
We can go in now!
Remember to keep a close eye on your money.
Not that I'm saying we have thieves inside, mind you.
Yeah, I'm really sorry you got dragged into that mess.
I should've known better.
Luffy, wait!
Do a better job of protecting me next time around!
Okay, no problem!
I got this!
I'm worried.
Dock One employs the strongest workers of the Galilaw Company.
We take on our most difficult requests here.
Come on, let's take a look inside.
Whoa!
It's super huge!
I knew it was going to be awesome!
I got this!
Dock One employs the strongest workers of the Galilaw Company.
We take on our most difficult requests here.
Come on, let's take a look inside.
Whoa!
It's super huge!
I knew it was going to be awesome, but it's even better up close!
No kidding!
Yeah!
Ooh, look over there!
They're building a big galleon!
I wonder who it's for!
Wow, they've got a full force working here.
Now, this way if you will.
Whoa!
You guys see that?
Iceberg's here!
Hey!
Look sharp for the boss, everyone!
Good morning, Mr. Iceberg!
Nice to see you here, sir!
Hey, boss, could you take a look at the outer panels for me?
Sure, I'll stop by later.
Lovely day you ate it, Mr. Iceberg!
Well, that depends on how the project's going.
We're actually ahead of schedule, sir!
I guess Ice Pops is pretty popular around here, huh?
In a place where skill is everything, it's only natural that he shines.
It's interesting.
Although shipbuilding has always been a thriving business, before Iceberg's time, it was divided
between seven competing companies.
Regardless, when he showed up, there was something about his talent that united everyone in the city.
With so many workers flocking to him, it wasn't long before he made the seven companies into one.
And five years ago, Galley Law was born.
His passion for shipbuilding has never diminished, and neither has the respect that the craftsmen show for him.
The people here take pride in their work so they don't bow down to anyone.
That goes for pirates and marine officers alike.
That's the spirit this shipyard embodies.
Hey, buddy, I hear you're a pretty good shipwright.
How'd you feel about joining my crew? Sound like fun?
What the hell are you trying to pull here, kid?
You insolent little wretch!
Now, now, he was trying to pay him a compliment.
He doesn't know any better.
Does this mean you sailed all the way to Water 7 without any shipwrights on your crew?
Yeah, that's one of the reasons why we're here.
We need to have our ship repaired, but we're looking for a new crew member, too.
We certainly have plenty of shipwrights to go around, but I wonder if any of them would be willing to join a pirate ship.
Well, if you can find someone who agrees to go with you, I won't get in the way.
You really mean it?
Wow!
I see why people like you.
My offer still stands, you know.
Well, I probably shouldn't.
I am the mayor.
So what?
By the way, Khalifa mentioned earlier that Nico Robin was a member of your crew.
Is that correct?
Sure is.
She's nice to have around since she's so smart.
What's up?
There's not something wrong with her, is there?
Oh, no.
So anyway, it's okay if I check out that ship up close, right?
Of course.
I wouldn't mind at all.
Thanks!
I could watch them do this stuff all day!
Keep it steady.
No need to rush.
We got this.
We gotta get a cannon like that to put on the Mary.
That'd be awesome!
Hm?
Whoa!
It's so shiny and long!
A real Timmy Culvering Cannon!
Wow!
They've really got everything!
I wonder what it feels like to fire one of those.
Here's our chance.
Looks like it's made of copper.
I bet it's super expensive.
Ooh!
I wonder if they'd let me try it out.
Oh, wait a sec!
We've got 300 million berries!
I almost forgot!
We can afford at least one of those, no problem!
Maybe two or three!
Did that guy with the nose leave already?
Robin was right there.
Where did she go?
Hm?
This way.
I know this smell.
I thought so.
It's bad enough that Robin ignored me,
but who was that guy in the mask she was with?
Wasn't Chopper, was it?
Sanji!
Speak of the devil.
Huh?
Kaku?
Where'd you run off to?
An assessment.
Wow!
You are fast, huh?
I take it you checked the ship?
That I did, Missy.
Now that's a coincidence.
We were wondering where you were.
They told me while they're here.
How was the ship?
About that.
Luffy!
Get down here!
Okay!
Be right there!
Gah!
What?
You better not be lying!
Cause if this is a joke, I'm sure as hell not laughing!
I wouldn't lie about something like that.
I'm gonna go crazy.
And the Renew kin Galvary sing some people up at the time.
I don't lie about something like this.
I'm a professional.
Something happen to Usopp?
Well, he was looking at the cannons over there
a second ago, but...
Hey, you there!
These bags are yours, aren't they?
Ugh, Usopp was supposed to be taking care of those.
But yeah, they're ours.
Thanks, buddy.
I can't believe that idiot wandering off at a time like this.
And how can I leave our precious money alone like that?
Your money?
Yeah, those bags you found have 200 million berries in them.
You're funny, kid.
You wish.
See ya.
Man, that's a good one.
So, how much do you think the repairs are gonna cost?
We've got plenty of money to spend,
and no price is too high for our Mary.
And while you're at it,
why don't you make her stronger, faster, as tough as nails,
and, of course, decked out with cannons?
I'd like some pretty engravings or some kind of decoration along the hull.
Also, can you guys renovate the inside?
Oh, and a big statue, too.
And when I say big, I mean huge, okay?
Not so fast.
Uh-huh.
That ship of yours,
she's gone on some really extraordinary journeys, hasn't she?
Uh...
Yeah, you bet. We've done it all.
A while back, we flew in the sky, then fell back down.
We climbed a big mountain, too.
So, you gotta work hard to fix her up extra good, okay?
You don't think I'm lying, do you?
That's not the issue.
Her battle scars are far worse than you think.
Um...
Then you're saying it's gonna take a long time for you to fix her?
No, ma'am.
It's not about the time.
It's not about skill, either.
I'm saying no one can fix her.
Not even us.
So that means the keel's damaged, huh?
That's right.
It looks like it's taken a real wallop.
No way!
We...
We've gone everywhere without any problems until now!
In theory,
even if we did everything we could,
the probability of your ship lasting till the next island
is zero.
Mary, tell me.
Is what he said true?
You'll never sail again?
No way to be killed again.
Transcription by CastingWords
Oh
on the next One Piece, pirate abduction incident
and a pirate ship that can only await her end.
I'm gonna be king of the pirates!